degreesearch.org 2015-06-01

# Privacy Policy

## Summary

This privacy policy was last updated on December 18, 2014.

This privacy statement describes how DegreeSearch.org collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: http://degreesearch.org/. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [info@degreesearch.org](mailto:info@degreesearch.org).

## Information We Collect Automatically

We collect various types of information from our visitors so we can adjust our site to meet our users’ needs and expectations. Some of this information is collected automatically through cookies and other information is collected when you register for any of our online services or when you request information from one of our partners.

The types of information your browser or Internet session automatically sends us each time you visit one of our sites, which we automatically collect and does not identify individual users, includes: 

  * Your browser, e.g., Internet Explorer, Netscape Navigator.
  * Your Internet domain, e.g., AOL, Netcom, Earthlink, etc.
  * Your computer's operating system, e.g., Windows, Macintosh, UNIX, Linux.
  * Your navigation path, i.e., the URLs of where you come to our site from, which of our pages you visit, and where you go as you leave.
  * Your IP address. This information lets us see how users are finding our sites, and it tells us which pages are visited the most often so we can make our Websites more useful.

## Use of Cookies

When you visit some of our sites, we use cookies to keep track of your information. This small piece of program code resides on your computer and stores your contact information for all of our request information sites. We do this so you are not required to re-enter your contact information. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site. You can remove these cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” directory. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site may be limited.

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by DegreeSearch.org only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

We use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show our ads on sites across the internet. Along with vendors like Google, we use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on a userâ€™s past visits to our website. We also use cookies to report how ad impressions and ad interactions relate to visits to our site. We use data from Googleâ€™s Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics.

## Web Beacons 

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information. 

## Information You Provide to Us

In addition to the information automatically collected by your browser, we also collect information that you provide to us when you request information about a particular school or educational program.

Our websites provide users the opportunity to request information from schools, and to learn about various education opportunities. These information request sites require users to provide us with contact information (name, address, phone number, email address, age, work experience, etc.) as well as information about their interest in one of our marketing partners (universities, colleges, test prep companies, financial aid providers, etc.). We collect this information that you provide, and may use it to make your future requests from our websites easier by pre-populating contact forms with the information that you have provided. We provide the contact information that you provide us to the marketing partner about which you requested information. Customer interest information is collected to determine what information the customer wishes to be sent.

## How We Use This Information

We use the information we automatically collect to help us better plan our sites to meet your Internet needs. Information you provide to us is used for marketing purposes, and may result in follow-up communications.

### Business Transactions:

In the event DegreeSearch.org goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified via email prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users’ personal information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

### Consent to Contact You:

You agree that when you provide information to DegreeSearch.org and check the unchecked box next to the language indicating your consent for us and schools to which you are matched to contact you, that checking the box constitutes your signature and your agreement that DegreeSearch.org may contact you by telephone (including at your wireless telephone number), email, text or SMS message, or pre-recorded message at the number(s) or email address you provided through this website through any means, including, using an automatic telephone dialing system or artificial pre-recorded voice. You understand and agree that this consent applies even if (i) your number is listed on a state or federal do-not-call list, (ii) your email is listed on any do-not-email list, or (iii) you previously unsubscribed from the DegreeSearch.org email list. You further agree that DegreeSearch.org may share your information with third parties in accordance with this policy, including with the schools with which you are matched.

### SMS/Text Messaging

  * Message and Data Rates May Apply. While there is no additional charge for DegreeSearch (powered by StrikeIron) text services. However, Message and Data Rates May Apply. Check with your carrier for rate information.
  * Users may receive up to 99 messages per month.
  * To end messaging, send **STOP** to 49502 (98789 in Canada). **END** , **CANCEL** , **REMOVE** , **UNSUBSCRIBE** , **QUIT** or **ARRET** also will stop the messages.
  * For more information, send **HELP** to 49502 (98789 in Canada). **INFO** and **AIDE** also will provide more information.
  * The DegreeSearch (powered by StrikeIron) Alerts service supports 433 carriers worldwide. The major US carriers such as Cingular, AT&T, T-Mobile, Verizon Wireless, Sprint and Alltel are fully supported. Canadian carriers such as Aliant Mobility, Bell Mobility, Fido Solutions, MTS Mobility, NorthernTel Mobility, Rogers Wireless, SaskTel Mobility, Telebec Mobilite, TELUS Mobility, and Virgin Mobile Canada are fully supported. For a complete list of carriers covered, please see [the list.](http://www.strikeiron.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/SMS-Mobile-Carriers-PDF.pdf)
  * Verizon Wireless is not responsible for any delayed or undelivered messages. Alerts sent via SMS may not be delivered to you if your phone is not in range of a transmission site, or if sufficient network capacity is not available at a particular time. Even within a coverage area, factors beyond the control of your wireless carrier may interfere with message delivery, including the customer's equipment, terrain, proximity to buildings, foliage, and weather. You acknowledge that urgent alerts may not be timely received and that your wireless carrier does not guarantee that alerts will be delivered.
  * For more information and updates about SMS/Text Messaging, visit: [alerts.strikeiron.com](http://alerts.strikeiron.com/)

### Legal Disclaimer:

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

### Service Providers:

We may provide your personal information to schools and call centers to contact you regarding your application for information. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

## Co-branding

At times we may enter into co-branded relationships. When we enter into these types of relationships we will share your name and email address in order for our co-branded partner to contact you with additional information.

Our privacy statement applies to the information collected on these co-branded sites. You should also read the privacy statement of our co-branded partner.

## Your Rights Our Obligations

The company respects the privacy of users visiting our sites and will abide by all applicable laws concerning the release of personal information. On an occasion we may use certain directory information that we have collected to send you information about products and services, or updates and other information we think may be of interest to you. We reserve the right to share data with third party partners. We may share this information with our marketing partners to bring similar information to your attention. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes. Please contact us to request your name and address be removed from our lists. If you do not want to receive our e-mail marketing, please submit a request to have your e-mail address removed [here](http://degreesearch.org/unsubscribe).

## Our Security Measures

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [info@degreesearch.org](mailto:info@degreesearch.org).

## Blogs

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [info@degreesearch.org](mailto:info@degreesearch.org). If in any case we are not be able to remove your personal information, we will let you know why.

## Customer Testimonials/Comments/Reviews

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [info@degreesearch.org](mailto:info@degreesearch.org).

## Links From Our Site To Other Sites

Some of our sites may contain links to other sites external to our sites. DegreeSearch.org is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any Web sites which we do not directly control.

## Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Correcting or Updating your Personal Information

Please note that users cannot update or delete previously submitted information. If your information (such as your email address) should change, we ask that you re-submit a registration form or request.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

### Contact information

  * DegreeSearch.org
  * 3098 Executive Parkway, Suite 300
  * Lehi, UT 84043
